Creating a Defect Opportunity Matrix
Welcome to this session on defect opportunities.
In this session, we’re going to take a look at the Golden Spur Ranch here.
And to help us understand defect opportunities.
What I've done, is I've identified a number of items given in column B. I'll blow that up for us.
In this case we're looking at people,
horses, dogs, goats, fish, cattle, tractors, equipment, trailers,
cars, motorcycles, structural, plumbing, heating, cooling, floors, irrigation, water, plants,
trees, tack, security, waste.
Now, all those things have to have activities.
We have the operation of, the maintenance of, the cleaning of, the purchasing of.
For example, the purchasing of food.
The licensing of trailers and cars.
The repair of electrical, mechanical things.
As I put an estimate in here. Let's say for example, I believe that
related to the maintenance of horses
that there is about 50 things that need to be done.
Therefore, there are 50 maintenance opportunities where horses are concerned.
Then I can look at, say, for example, the licensing of dogs.
I know that we've got six dogs around here. They all need collars.
So, that's another 10 opportunities.
In other words this, there's 10 opportunities for something to go wrong.
Whoops, excuse me, I put 10 in, I meant six. I’ve got too many dogs.
There would be six opportunities, for not getting licenses.
Each year.
There would be 50 opportunities to not properly maintain the horses.
Now, that's an example. Let’s take another one.
Automobiles, licenses.
Equipment, tractors. The maintenance of those tractors.
In this case there's a big one and a small one.
Insurance for them, see. The law requires that we have an insurance card in every vehicle.
So, that's an opportunity for something to go wrong.
So, I can carefully sit down and think through this, over a couple of hours and a cup of coffee.
And identify, across the whole matrix,
the total number of opportunities
for defect that exists in a year or a week or a month or quarterly,
at the Golden Spur Ranch.
Then I could create check sheets. Every time I see something mark it.
This failed to happen. That didn't get done.
Then I can get my defects per opportunity, convert that to a Sigma.
There is another example. At the personal level,
using the Golden Spur Ranch as an example.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.